I want you
to imagine what
that would feel
like if you're
a 12-year-old
kid and
everybody in
the room
starts praying,
and now you,
the atheist kid,
or Muslim kid,
Hindu, Jewish, whatever
your faith
or none...
This amendment would
require every school
board to adopt
a policy requiring
its K-12 public
schools to
allow student-initiated,
student-led prayer.
Now, the first
thing that listeners
need to know
is that
Alabama students
already have
the right
to pray.
The problem with
Amendment 3 is
it requires all
public schools to
create an
official government
platform for
student-led prayer.
Now, during debate
on this amendment,
an Alabama lawmaker
proposed a moment
of silence,
so every
child could
reflect, pray,
and just
sit quietly.
But the bill's
author rejected it
and said, quote,
we want the
students to
hear it.
Now, we've heard
about these airline
preachers lately, and
commercial airlines don't
even allow them
to turn a
captive cabin
of passengers
into their
personal pulpit.
So I would
hope that we
do not allow
the government to
do the
same thing
in public
school classrooms.
However, supporters
will say,
well, students can
just opt out.
Now, I want
you to imagine
what that would
feel like if
you're a 12-year-old
kid and
everybody in
the room
starts praying,
and now you,
the atheist kid,
or Muslim kid,
Hindu, Jewish,
whatever your
faith or
none, you
are now
left with the
burden of having
to figure out
either to remove
yourself in front
of your classmates
or just sit
there and
be coerced
into hearing
something that
you don't
want to.
It's hugely problematic.
And as a
parent to two
kids in public
schools, I
look at
this as
a parents'
rights issue
as well.
The bill's author
talked about children
who aren't
getting prayer
at home.
Well, let me
tell you, that
is not the
government's job to
dictate or to
decide what
kids should
be learning
in terms
of religion
at home. And
that's the problem
with Christian nationalism
and people in
positions of power
that can
use their
authority to
legislate their
narrow-minded religious
perspectives onto
everyone else.
This is wildly
unconstitutional, and it's
problematic, and we
are urging everyone
in Alabama
to vote
no on
Amendment 3.